Rachael Charewicz

Full Stack Software Engineer

Kennebunk, Maine | Github | LinkedIn

SUMMARY

As a versatile and organized full stack software engineer with a focus in React, I have 5+ years of experience providing value to stakeholders by transforming business requirements into elegant yet practical web solutions. I have a passion for mentoring and building company culture as well as a knack for tactful and diplomatic communication with clients and providing clarity and support for my team.

SKILLS & TECHNOLOGIES

React, TypeScript, Node.js, JavaScript, MySQL, MongoDB, Payload CMS, Next.js, NestJS, Material UI, CSS, HTML, Jest, Selenium, PHP, Laravel, Figma, Tailwind CSS, Cypress

EXPERIENCE

WhereWeGo – New Orleans, LA (SaaS startup supporting workforce development orgs)
Full Stack Software Developer | October 2024 – PRESENT

- Created a new user onboarding flow that implemented cross-subdomain authentication to randomly direct users either to a classic or AI experience; implemented Google Analytics and internal event tracking to gain insight into user preferences
- Led full-stack development of a job catalog system which involved implementing a
 responsive job search interface with advanced filtering capabilities, URL-persisted
 search states for shareable results, and mobile-optimized job card displays integrated
 with real CMS data
- Organized and moderated a two-day, company-wide AI Summit to foster alignment on the company's AI best practices
- Worked with a UI designer to advocate for accessibility standards, shape user experience improvements, and suggest time-saving design decisions
- Led a committee to address the bottleneck of pull request reviews leading up to scheduled launches; experimental workflow shifts resulting from the committee improved developer experience and the timely completion of peer reviews
- Provided clear, concise release notes and recorded regular video demos for each

project, offering visibility for project managers, teammates, and clients that conveyed both the technical and non-technical details of various builds

Datamura Solutions – Seabrook, NH (Data optimization consulting startup serving a Fortune 500 pharmaceutical company)

Software Engineer II | February 2023 – September 2024 **Software Engineer I** | March 2022 – February 2023

- Led and contributed to major projects for a React and Node operations portal serving multiple R&D sites across North America for a Fortune 500 pharmaceutical company
- Crafted a custom form builder as a foundation to create a user feedback and request portal, transforming a process that was previously conducted exclusively via email
- Managed a project to design and construct a system for tracking and reporting on environmental sustainability metrics data, reducing manual data entry and margin for error
- Partnered with another developer to design and build a hierarchical data management interface for facility assets, streamlining access to crucial metadata required for maintenance
- Reimagined an ineffective Excel project tracking process into a standardized web-based platform in order to increase accessibility to all construction project details, including financial tracking, project updates, and progress visuals for upper-level management
- Designed and built an administrative portal in Laravel (PHP) and Vue which utilized a
 Redis-based job queue and RESTful APIs to integrate with a video hosting platform,
 substantially reducing the need for manual data entry and permission configuration
- Created automated integration tests using Jest and Selenium
- Architected database structures, created entity relationship diagrams, and wrote SQL
 Server stored procedures and queries
- Mentored and guided the development team through pair programming, code reviews, and debugging sessions
- Created high fidelity designs, wireframes, and prototypes using Figma
- Organized project requirements into detailed technical specifications
- Collaborated with customers, stakeholders, and product managers to gather requirements and architect effective solutions for business challenges
- Contributed marketing copy to support sales and marketing efforts
- Redesigned the company website to improve visual appeal and distilled the existing verbose marketing copy to better highlight the company's key services

GYK Antler – Manchester, NH (Integrated advertising agency for major brands)

Junior Web Developer | April 2020 – April 2022

- Built dynamic, responsive landing page templates and led the client through training on the content management system
- Implemented a new brand style and functionality for an existing site in support of a rebranding campaign; provided technical and educational support to the client in regard to the new features
- Built promotional pop-ups, landing pages, and responsive HTML email templates to support marketing initiatives, partnering with SEO Specialists to implement tracking and maximize conformity with SEO best practices
- Worked closely with project managers to implement functionality necessary to launch an e-commerce site

EDUCATION

Full Stack Development Certification

University of New Hampshire, Portsmouth, NH

September 2019 - March 2020

BA in Women's, Gender, and Sexuality Studies, magna cum laude Allegheny College, Meadville, PA

August 2013 - May 2017